<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Verummeum</title>
    <link>https://verummeum.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Verummeum</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 14:25:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://verummeum.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Search, comments and an image viewer with Hugo</title>
      <link>https://verummeum.com/blog/2018/09/16/hugo-advanced-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 14:25:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://verummeum.com/blog/2018/09/16/hugo-advanced-features/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href=&#34;https://verummeum.com/blog/2018/09/02/how-verummeum-is-build/&#34;&gt;previous article&lt;/a&gt; I wrote about why I chose Hugo, a static site generator, as the framework on which to build Verummeum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I would like to go more in depth on the more advanced features I was able to integrate into Verummeum using Hugo. I hope this guide will be interesting for anyone who would like to know about the possibilities of static site generators in general, and of Hugo specifically. I myself underestimated the capabilities of static site generators until recently when I started doing some research, and I am happy to share what I have learned in this article.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Voyager Live 18.04.1 Review</title>
      <link>https://verummeum.com/blog/2018/09/09/voyager-live-review-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 18:34:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://verummeum.com/blog/2018/09/09/voyager-live-review-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://voyagerlive.org/&#34;&gt;Voyager Live&lt;/a&gt; is a Xubuntu based Linux distribution, offering a heavily themed XFCE desktop. This distribution aims to deliver the best user experience by providing an aesthetically pleasing and immersive desktop environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latest release of Voyager Live is based on the 18.04 Bionic Beaver long term support release of Xubuntu which is supported for 3 years. This is the version we will take a look at in this article.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Verummeum is built, Hugo static site generator</title>
      <link>https://verummeum.com/blog/2018/09/02/how-verummeum-is-build/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 14:19:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://verummeum.com/blog/2018/09/02/how-verummeum-is-build/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Before I started building Verummeum I compared a number of different frameworks and content management systems.
After researching the advantages and disadvantages of the different choices available, I finally decided to create Verummeum using Hugo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I made the choice to use Hugo I first decided that I wanted to create Verummeum as a static website. A static website has a number of advantages compared to a dynamic website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PCLinuxOS KDE Review</title>
      <link>https://verummeum.com/blog/2018/08/25/pclinuxos-review-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://verummeum.com/blog/2018/08/25/pclinuxos-review-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.pclinuxos.com/&#34;&gt;PCLinuxOS&lt;/a&gt; is a rolling release Linux distribution, offering a KDE and a MATE desktop version. Besides these official versions, other community maintained flavors for other desktop environments are available. This review is based on the KDE version of PCLinuxOS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The distribution is based on Mandriva Linux and uses RPM packages. It is a rolling release distribution that favors stability over providing bleeding edge software.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>