<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Guide on Verummeum</title>
    <link>https://verummeum.com/tags/guide/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Guide on Verummeum</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 16:22:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://verummeum.com/tags/guide/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>KDE Connect: Let Android and Linux devices communicate</title>
      <link>https://verummeum.com/kde-connect/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 16:22:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://verummeum.com/kde-connect/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you interested in receiving Android notifications on your Linux desktop or are you in need of an easy way to transfer data between Android and Linux devices? In this article we will take a look at &lt;a href=&#34;https://community.kde.org/KDEConnect&#34;&gt;KDE Connect&lt;/a&gt;, a free and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/KDE/kdeconnect-kde&#34;&gt;open-source&lt;/a&gt; project that allows you to easily set up communication between Android and Linux devices.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google free Android</title>
      <link>https://verummeum.com/google-free-android/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 16:20:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://verummeum.com/google-free-android/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Is it possible to have a usable Android device without Google services or apps installed? Are there open-source, or at least more privacy friendly, alternatives to the Google apps and services most Android users depend on? I have been experimenting with my Android smartphone to find an answer to these questions. With this article I want to share how I have tried to achieve a Google free Android phone and what other options are available or will be available to you in the near future to also obtain a Google free Android device.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search, comments and an image viewer with Hugo</title>
      <link>https://verummeum.com/hugo-advanced-features/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 14:25:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://verummeum.com/hugo-advanced-features/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href=&#34;https://verummeum.com/how-verummeum-is-build/&#34;&gt;previous article&lt;/a&gt; I wrote about why I chose Hugo, a static site generator, as the framework on which to build Verummeum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I would like to go more in depth on the more advanced features I was able to integrate into Verummeum using Hugo. I hope this guide will be interesting for anyone who would like to know about the possibilities of static site generators in general, and of Hugo specifically. I myself underestimated the capabilities of static site generators until recently when I started doing some research, and I am happy to share what I have learned in this article.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Verummeum is built, Hugo static site generator</title>
      <link>https://verummeum.com/how-verummeum-is-built/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 14:19:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://verummeum.com/how-verummeum-is-built/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Before I started building Verummeum I compared a number of different frameworks and content management systems.
After researching the advantages and disadvantages of the different choices available, I finally decided to create Verummeum using Hugo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I made the choice to use Hugo I first decided that I wanted to create Verummeum as a static website. A static website has a number of advantages compared to a dynamic website.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>